Noor Alhijab

Burke, VA | (585) 454-9410 | noor.m.alhijab@gmail.com

Linkedln | Portfolio | GitHub

Software Developer with 3+ years of experience using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, SASS/SCSS, ES6, and Visual Studio in an Agile environment to create innovative solutions and develop software applications. Strong knowledge of IT networking, Microsoft Team Foundation Server and AWS Cloud Practitioner.

SKILLS & Certifications

Programming: JavaScript, HTML5, CSS3, SASS, ES6 Cloud: Microsoft Azure, Amazon Web Services

Tools: AJAX, API, Visual Studio Code Certifications: Microsoft Azure Fundamentals, AWS Cloud

Version Control: Git, GitHub Practitioner

Methodologies: Agile

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

AWS Solutions Architect Associate program/ AWS CloudUp for Her

06/2023 - Present

- Solve business challenges by designing and optimizing cloud solutions using AWS services, the best practices, and the AWS Well-Architected Framework
- Build serverless application on AWS using service like Lambda, SQS, SNS, Kinesis, Aurora, S3, DynamoDB
- Implement cloud compute solutions, storage, databases using variety of AWS services such as EC2, S3, IAM Security Groups, Auto Scaling, ELB, RDS, ECR and VPC

Front-end Developer/ Freelance

01/2022 - Present

- Design, develop, and implement web applications using JavaScript, HTML, CSS, and SASS to enhance user experiences
 and optimize interface for improved functionality
- Develop fully functional multi-page website using HTML, CSS, and CSS Grid, improving usability access
- Work in Agile environment to successfully develop web applications

Software Developer Apprentice/ Code the Dream

08/2021 -12/2021

- Mastered advanced programming topics focused on JavaScript (functions, loops, arrays, objects, DOM manipulation), HTML, and CSS
- Built foundation to Git, and gained knowledge of debugging and Internet
- Developed skills in AJAX and APT fetch, and built portfolio page using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS

PROJECTS

Easybank Landing Page Master | Code

- Created user-friendly website by converting mock-ups to meet user needs and requirements
- Utilized JavaScript to create drop-down menu functionality and Grid for layout

Insure Landing Page | Code

- Created fully responsive landing page according to designs provided by designer and end-user using JavaScript, HTML5, and CSS3 for mobile navigation toggle
- · Implemented website to provide users with optimal layout depending on device screen size

Dashboard with Theme Switcher | Code

- Implemented responsive social media dashboard with light and dark theme toggle using JavaScript, HTML, and CSS
- Used CSS Flexbox skills and implemented color theme switcher with JavaScript
- Developed website to allow users to toggle color theme based on preference and view ideal layout

Template NA News I Code

- · Created multi-age website coded in HTML, CSS, and CSS Grid, honing skills in Grid Layout
- · Enhanced user experience and accomplished website objectives by building site structure, navigation, and usability

EDUCATION

2008 Bachelor of Science (BS), Software Engineering, Baghdad College of Economic Sciences University

2021 The Complete JavaScript Course, Udemy

2021 Modern HTML & CSS from the Beginning, Udemy

2021 Modern HTML & CSS from the Beginning, Udemy

Languages: English, Arabic